<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: itsbspoke | Hello, I'm Jim Van Fleet]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.jimvanfleet.com//blog/categories/itsbspoke/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.jimvanfleet.com//"/>
  <updated>2021-06-09T11:42:11-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.jimvanfleet.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jim Van Fleet]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jim@jimvanfleet.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The end of an era]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.jimvanfleet.com//blog/2015/04/16/the-end-of-an-era/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-16T15:54:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.jimvanfleet.com//blog/2015/04/16/the-end-of-an-era</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I notified my employees and clients this week that <a href="http://www.itsbspoke.com/">itsbspoke</a> will cease operations on May 31, with the month of May serving as a transition and severance period for the team.  I am now looking for full-time employment starting June 1.</p>

<p>I feel such gratitude that I’ve had an opportunity to work with wonderful teammates and clients during the past five years.  I knew there were significant entrepreneurial risks as I grew my team and expanded the scope of itsbspoke.  Unfortunately, the opportunities I envisioned as a business owner did not materialize.</p>

<p>I am proud of what we have accomplished with our clients, with Charlotte&rsquo;s startup community, and through the civic projects we&rsquo;ve undertaken to benefit the City itself.  <a href="http://www.pitchbreakfast.com/">PitchBreakfast</a> and <a href="http://charlotte.startupweekend.org">Charlotte Startup Weekend</a> are now fixtures in the entrepreneurial community.  <a href="http://www.codeforcharlotte.org/">Code for Charlotte</a> is now improving quality of life for all Charlotteans.  <a href="http://crtec.us/">CRTEC</a> and <a href="http://it-ology.org/en/CharlotteNC.aspx">it-ology</a> contribute significantly to the technology community here.  I’ve made so many new friends through my newsletter, and heard from so many that it has made a difference for them, as well.</p>

<p>I may return to these commitments in time, but now I&rsquo;m eager to open a new chapter in my professional life, a chapter with more focused personal aspirations and a greater dedication to fulfulling the growing needs of my young family.</p>

<h2>What’s next for me:</h2>

<p>I am looking for full-time employment with a target first day of June 1.  I am committed to staying in Charlotte.  My ideal position would allow me to achieve the following goals:</p>

<h3>Work toward a more just world</h3>

<p>I believe in the possibilities of a world of with abundant economic opportunity and justice.  I’ve loved getting involved in the civic technology community her in Charlotte.  The opportunity to make a difference in my community, and other communities, through the power of technology is important to me.</p>

<h3>Develop myself as a manager and leader</h3>

<p>My next step is not becoming 10x more effective as a software engineer, but in creating and leading teams that can reach new heights and accomplish what was once thought impossible.  I might not have an MBA, but I&rsquo;ve led teams down the road of hard knocks, built the relationships necessary and achieved success more often than not.  This represents the next phase for me.</p>

<h3>Ditch the headphones</h3>

<p>I no longer feel the need to prove I can slap on the headphones and crush code to make a delivery date.  I’m certainly not opposed to bringing my whole self to any assignment, and of course that capability is valuable.</p>

<p>I spent the first twenty years of my career learning all I could about how to deliver and operate successful web applications that scaled.  While that experience certainly helps avoid expensive mistakes and failures, I&rsquo;ve learned that technology alone is never ultimately responsible for a project’s success.  My opportunities for growth involve attending to the business, organizational, and leadership dimensions of succes, and that requires setting the headphones aside.</p>

<h2>Get in touch</h2>

<p>With these goals in mind, if you think you or your firm might be a good fit for me, or if you know of someone I should speak with about possible opportunities, let me know <a href="mailto:jim.van.fleet+job@gmail.com">via email</a> or <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/jimvanfleet">LinkedIn</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
